Contact

Homestead, FL 305 332 7816 (Mobile) jorgejgarciarn@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jorge-j-garcia-rn-cmsrn (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing Informatics Teamwork Tableau

Languages

Spanish (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional)

Certifications

Registered Nurse

Basic Life Support for Healthcare Providers (BLS)

Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS)

Certified Medical-Surgical Registered Nurse (CMSRN)

Honors-Awards

MSN - Magna Cum Laude

Jorge J Garcia, MSN RN CMSRN

Clinical Informatics Specialist at Baptist Health South Florida Homestead, Florida

Summary

Board certified medical-surgical Registered Nurse with experience as a bedside RN in an acute care setting; as well as relief charge nurse, also within an acute care setting. As an expert RN within my organization, I am skilled in team management and delegation, managing the eMAR with proper order entry as well as medication administration, appropriately handling medical equipment, and Healthcare Information Technology (HIT). I have a strong background in healthcare services, also having obtained a Master of Science in Nursing Informatics.

As a nurse I believe that:

People are unique individuals, who are deserving of respect, dignity, care, compassion and excellent service. People are holistic beings (body, mind and spirit) and are different from, and more than, a sum of their parts. The environment is the internal and external world as perceived and experienced by the person. All aspects of the health care environment must support the perception of well-being for all people who enter into it.

Experience

Baptist Health South Florida 2 years 7 months Clinical Informatics Specialist March 2020 - Present (4 months) Coral Gables, Florida, United States

Registered Nurse

December 2017 - March 2020 (2 years 4 months)

Homestead, Florida

Independently maintained safe and effective care to patients with different acuity levels in a time-restricted and demanding environment; constantly communicated and collaborated with physicians and other healthcare professionals to ensure optimal care deliver to patients in a timely manner. Charge Nurses Relief (PCS Relief): Collaborates with medical, clinical and operational leadership in planning, coordinating and monitoring floor workflow; Serving as an expert and resource for the Medical, Nurses and/or Clinical-Ancillary staff.

Kendall Regional Medical Center
Registered Nurse
February 2016 - August 2018 (2 years 7 months)
Miami/Fort Lauderdale Area

Manage for post-surgical Joint Replacements, Trauma, Fractures, Cardiac, Stroke and Burns patients; IV therapy, Central and Mid-Lines, PCA pumps, Blood transfusions, Tubes and Drains; Manage pain effectively; Reviewed patient data for surgery and reported findings to appropriate staff members; Ensured accurate patient and family comprehension of treatment plans; Coordinate care, in collaboration with a wide array of healthcare professionals.

Coral Reef Nursing and Rehab Registered Nurse October 2015 - February 2016 (5 months) Miami/Fort Lauderdale Area

Perform physical exams and health histories; Provide health promotion, counseling and education; Administer medications, wound care; Interpret patient information and make critical decisions about needed actions; Coordinate care.

Education

West Coast University

Master of Science - MS, Nursing (2016 - 2020)

CENSA International College

Associate's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2013 - 2014)

Dade Medical College-Miami
Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse (2012 - 2013)